Hi, noon in old Cheyenne. I'd like to
call the April 21st meeting of the
finance committee to order. If you're in
the room, please be sure your cell
phones are on vibrator turned off. When
making public comment, clearly identify
yourself. Making public comment online,
use the raised hand function.
uh in person, turn on the microphone and
at the end of the agenda, there will be
no additional business discussed. And as
always, all communications go through
the chair. With that clerk, first item
>> number 15, ordinance, third reading,
appropriating money for the Reed Avenue
corridor project.
Staff report,
no staff report.
Well, we're pretty aware of what it is.
So, uh, we'll go to public comment.
Any public comment in the room?
Good afternoon, Sophia May Cheyenne, DDA
executive director. Um the as I noted
last session, last finance committee
um actually apologize I wasn't here. Um
the during council meeting uh the
Cheyenne DDA supports this appropriation
of the 5 million for the read rail
corridor. Uh we believe that although
the scope has changed significantly
since the uh feasibility study that was
produced the
plan the design that's moving forward is
more like an urban greenway and we
believe that that connectivity that
utilization of the space um throughout
the summer months in downtown Cheyenne
as well as providing an opportunity for
the reinvestment into the historical
area of downtown is really critical and
um we support this And please let me
know if you have any questions.
>> Any comments or questions from the
committee to our DDA director?
>> Any public comment online?
Seeing none, can I get a motion?
>> Mr. Chairman, um I move to uh approve uh
on third and final reading.
>> Second.
It's been moved by Councilman Wolf,
second by Councilman White. Any further
discussion?
All in favor signify by saying I.
>> I.
>> Oppose. No.
The recommendation of the finance
committee at the next meeting of the
governing body will be to approve. Next
item.
>> Number 23. Resolution approving a
proposition to impose the 1% specific
purpose sales and use tax in Larmy
County, state of Wyoming, for the
exclusive purpose of funding specific
purposes for spec for specific amounts.
The propositions to be voted on at the
election to be held on August 18th of
2026.
>> Staff report
Norman um through you to the committee.
Um before you is a proposition um
outlining all of the ballot items um
across the county um for consideration
and approval. This will be identical
across all governing bodies. Um, and
this will be what will go before the
voters for approval. And I'm happy to
answer any questions.
>> Any comments or questions from the
committee to the chief of staff?
>> Uh, Mr. Chairman,
>> Councilman Wolf.
>> Uh, thank you, Mr. Chairman, through
you. Um,
Madam Chief of Staff, I just want to
express my appreciation to you and to
the mayor and um to all the people that
you worked so hard with um on this is
such an important matter uh for the
community Cheyenne for the county and
for the small towns and uh your efforts
and the mayor's efforts and your staff
are very much appreciated. Thank you.
>> Thank you.
Councilman Moody.
>> Thank you, Mr. Chairman. Through you.
Um, Miss Ash, just a question so that
way the public knows for um, Proposition
One where it says Cheyenne Le's Hitching
Post District Psych Improvements. You
just want to tell them that's where the
PRCA rodeo relocation. Is that correct?
>> Uh, Mr. Chairman, through you. Yes, that
is my understanding. Um, that is a
county sponsored initiative.
That's all I have. Thank you.
>> Any further comments or questions from
the committee to the chief of staff?
>> Go to public comment in the room
on six penny.
Any public comment online?
See then can I get a motion?
>> Uh Mr. Chairman, um I move to approve on
third and final reading.
>> Second.
>> Yeah, it has to be moved to adopt.
>> Oh, I'm sorry. I would move to approve.
Adopt. Adopt.
>> Yeah.
>> Second.
>> It's been moved by Councilman Wolf,
second by Councilman White. Any further
comments or discussions from the
committee?
All in favor? signify by saying I
>> I
>> I.
>> Seeing there's none opposed, the
recommendation of the finance committee
at the next meeting of the governing
body will be to adopt. Next item,
please.
Number 26 resolution approving an
increase of the budget of the Cheyenne
Downtown Development Authority for the
fiscal year beginning July 1st, 2025 and
ending June 30th, 2026.
>> Staff report.
Hello, Sophia Mays, executive director
of the DDA. Again, for the record, the
item before you is the u the fiscal year
2026 DDA budget increase uh that we were
asking for governing body approval. The
adopted budget at the beginning of 2026,
fiscal year 2026 was 720,450
and it was established uh based on prior
year's operating expenses. Due to the
expansion and increase of DDA activities
and um grant administration, the staff
sees the urgent need to increase the
budget beyond the original projections.
This budget was also produced uh when I
was about
I want to say two months in, one month
in. Uh so there was no way for us to
accurately project how um we would be
operating through this year.
Since 2023, the DDA has managed budget
adjustments through quarterly amendments
v via board approval. However, the
Wyoming state statute 159218
requires the DDA to adopt a budget
requiring the governing body to review
and approve the adopted budget and any
changes going forward. This will be the
process for any amendments if necessary.
Some key changes to this budget are an
increase in the revenue line items, uh
5,000 to increase for the Laramie County
grant. This was a clerical error. We
actually received $10,000 as that grant
and 92,824
increase to the revenue from reserves to
cover increases to our operating budget.
The expenses that we are increasing in
this amendment are include um auditing
and accounting services for CPA to
assist with staff capacity. We are also
asking to increase 37,250 for the
downtown planter program. That's an
expansion of scope to have year- round
maintenance for that planter. The um
we're anticipating about 5,624
increase to the banner program. We're
planning to replace all of the banners
downtown and um 22,275
increase to our sponsorship line item.
The way that we accounted for this last
year was we split it between the two
fiscal years and we would prefer to
simply have it in in this current fiscal
year for us to pay that that sponsorship
for its on the plaza.
Uh we also have some increases to our
grant programs. The facade improvement
program 11,175
and then 17,500 to our capital
improvement program uh grant program.
there has been an increase of requests
for grants and uh we would like to be
able to serve those applicants
appropriately. Um please let me know I
if you have any questions and uh thank
you so much.
>> Any comments or questions from the
committee to the DDA director?
>> Mr. Chairman,
>> Councilman Moody.
>> Yeah, I will have several questions, Mr.
Chairman. Uh thank you, Miss May. I
appreciate that. Um just a couple
questions. So, for the communications
plan, um why is it going up from 10,000
to 130,000? And I'm looking at uh this
page right here so the public can see it
as well, too. Why is it uh going up so
much?
>> You Mr. Chair,
we knew that at the beginning of the
fiscal year, uh we knew that we wanted
to do a comprehensive communications
plan. We did not
accurately estimate how much we would
need for that. uh we put in a a line
item to with the assumption that we
could amend it the budget later and um
once we got the the proposals back we
found that the chosen proposal was
130,000 uh board approval decided that
that was the best option because there
were options of a simple website redo or
a comprehensive communications um the
option that we chose included brand
standards, updates, um a campaign
strategy outline, complete uh website
development, and then also a change
order of um video content. And so this
will include, I believe, a one minute
sizzle reel showing all of downtown for
us to promote on social media, um other
videos throughout downtown and then
throughout the region as well. And then
a couple of 15-second videos for, you
know, smaller promotions of downtown. Um
this was a lack of foresight on my part.
Uh I will acknowledge that. But we we
believe wholeheartedly that it was money
well spent and um as most of you saw in
the work session with city council, it
is already giving us returns in our
communications.
>> Mr. Chairman, go ahead.
>> All right. Uh thank you ma'am for that
answer. um who's going to be the main
driver of this, the company or who has
already been a contract signed or
potentially approved yet for this?
Mr. Chair, through you. Uh yes, the
communications plan is almost complete.
Uh the
way that the DDA has historically or
since 2023 has amended our budget has
just been through quarterly amendments
with the board. uh we did not realize
that it needed to go through the
governing body which is why I stand
before you today um to correct that that
oversight that we had. So the contract
was signed last April I believe and it
is almost complete.
>> Mr. Chair,
>> go ahead. Uh name of the company please.
>> Mr. Chair through you. I apologize. It
is West Edge Collective or sorry not
collective just West Edge.
>> Mr. Ch.
>> All right. Thank you Mr. Chairman
through you. Uh thank you for that. Um,
another question I have is for the uh
downtown planner program, it's going up
$37,250.
I mean, this year is an anomaly, but we
do have a short growing season. Just
curious why that's going up so much.
>> Mr. Chair, through you, the planter
program in past, we would secure the
contract in June and it would last until
October. Um and that was for believe we
have around 100 planters and
we estimated around 45,000. Um last year
the budget was 45,000. We had very good
responses and feedback for it but one of
the top was that there were not enough
flowers. So we increased the flower
amount. We've also added eight um
planters as part of a water efficient
pilot program to see if we would like to
replace the other planters downtown. Um
this is something that the DDA has been
looking at for a few years now. I think
since 2018 or 2019, looking at those
types of planters. So we thought it
would be better to add just eight, see
how they do, see how the community
reacts, and see if we want to move
forward with that. So there's eight
additional planters that need to be
planted. We also increased the scope of
the vendor because what we noticed was
during the winter months the planters
are just dead and and um some people
like to use them as trash recepticles.
So part of that is for the vendor to
come in ensure that there's weekly
maintenance cleaning them out. But we
also want to um see if there's a way we
can add winter displays such as
evergreens or lighted displays within a
couple of those planters. um that's not
reflected in excuse me that's not
reflected in this budget that would be
in next year's budget but the whole
scope of the contract um paired with
what we paid for last summer from July
to October to also what we need from
right now when the vendors are starting
planting and sourcing to July 1st or
June 30th that's the increase that we
need
>> go ahead thank you mayor for that answer
um I'm looking at IM712 12 again if the
public's following along. Uh why is
there no graffiti removal even budgeted
for that
for downtown
>> Mr. through you? The graffiti removal
program was a codified permit program,
excuse me, codified program um in city
code. It did have a sunset and I believe
it sunseted either in 2023 or 2024. So
that is not a codified program and um we
have not chosen to renew it at this
time.
>> Just more questions.
>> Yep. Go ahead.
>> All right. Thank you. Um I'm looking at
the sidewalk match program. Just curious
why it's only uh $85,000.
I'd say it's probably the number one
issue, the basics, having nice
sidewalks, the brick repaired.
>> Mr. Chair, through you. The sidewalk
improvement program. This was a pilot
program started. I want Councilman
Lebornne would be able to to um add more
to this specifically, but I believe it
was mid 2024, early 2024 when it was um
when that resolution was passed. This is
a program that the DDA works with the
city 1% construction division to
implement. The reserves were 100,000 for
that entire pilot program. It started as
a pilot just to see if we could fix some
of these high traffic, high key priority
sidewalks. Um, we've kept that 100,000
through the this current fiscal year and
we're still at 85,000. Our intention is
to get the data. We have about I think
nine applications currently in that
we're going to try and get before the
summer, get those sidewalks fixed, and
then for next budget year, we're
planning to budget an additional 100,000
to try to fix more sidewalks.
>> All right. Thank you. I'm done, Mr.
Chairman.
>> Any further questions from the
committee?
>> Councilman Wolf.
>> Mr. Chairman, thank you uh through you.
Um, thank you, Director Mays. Um,
appreciate all your work on this. What's
the reaction of your members been to the
communications plan that you've been
working so hard on?
>> Mr. Chairman, uh to Councilman Wolf, uh
we actually do not have members, but we
do have stakeholders such as property
owners, business owners, residents of
downtown. The reaction has been quite um
quite surprising actually in a good way.
We were uh we had a staff meeting this
morning talking about our downtown um
strategy that we're we're developing
right now for this summer. And our
marketing um person, she was showing the
data compared from last year to this
year. And we had last year in our
sentiment survey, we had a a 32%
um confidence in our communications that
people that took that survey felt
confident. They felt we were
communicating effectively, that they um
had access to what we were doing. This
year it was about I think in the low 70s
um low and then low 60s from that range
for a variety of communication topics
and um so we see that as as an immense
increase. Our social media is up um the
way that people are discussing us on
social media and in the community has
shifted from that reputation of kind of
being more event focused to more
development focused which is what we
were looking for. So, a lot of that
correction and um uh solitting
ourselves, solidifying ourselves as a
downtown development authority and being
a resource for people downtown has um
been dramatic, I would say.
>> Councilman White, you have any questions
for the DDA director?
>> Thank you, Mr. Chair. Sophia, just just
point of clarification, and I think most
of us know this, but
the company that DDA contracted with to
do the communications plan, West Edge,
that is a local company. Correct.
>> Mr. Chair, threw you to Councilman
White. That is correct. Um, West Edge is
actually in our downtown district. So
they are not only a firm that we're
working with, but they're a stakeholder
and they have worked with other other
firms within um Cheyenne, Visit
Cheyenne, the MO and a few others.
>> Y just wanted to get that on the record.
Thanks, Sophia.
>> Okay, thank you Sophia. Um we'll go to
public comment in the room.
Any public comment online?
>> Mr. Miller, you should be able to unmute
yourself.
>> Go ahead, sir.
>> Can you hear me?
>> We can.
>> Um, okay.
Uh, Mr. Chairman, members of the finance
committee, Charles Miller. I'm speaking
today to place a formal notice of
systemic fiscal risk on the
administrative record. As the committee
tasked with the financial integrity of
the city, you are currently being asked
to retroactively rubber stamp a $130,000
budget expansion for a DDA PR campaign
that was spent without your prior
approval. You're doing this while the
administration actively conceals the
true catastrophic costs of its
industrial expansion. Yesterday, the
public services committee generated a
massive un ununderwritten legal
liability for this city.
>> Point of order, Mr. Miller, that's not
what we're discussing here in finance.
What happened yesterday? We're on the DA
budget.
>> I'm sorry, but this is tied in directly
to it. Um,
>> point of order, Mr. Chairman. I don't
believe that it is.
>> Yeah, it's not, Mr. Miller. Stick to the
DDA budget, sir.
Um well, you cannot claim fiscal
responsibility by retroactively funding
$130,000
uh sizzle reels while simultaneously
passing the hidden costs of industrial
heavy metal filtration onto the taxpayer
and exposing the city treasury to first
amendment lawsuits until the
administration can produce
>> point of border. Mr.
transparently audit and
>> I object to my order that
>> Mr. Miller, you stick to the DDA budget.
>> Oh,
>> that's the second time you were called
out of order. Stick to the DDA budget.
>> How much time do I have left here?
about a minute.
Um,
the DDA has zero dollars budgeted for
graffiti removal and only 85,000
allocated for actual physical sidewalk
repairs. yet they retroactively spent
$130,000 on a communications plan uh to
improve their reputation. Um
th this this just isn't good. It's it's
it's really not good. And um I think you
guys know it. There's there's been a lot
of controversy with this particular um
uh group here in the past with audit
audits. Um, I don't know if you guys can
speak to uh how they've changed since
the uh, you know, failing of the audit.
I think it was two years ago. Um, is it
possible for you to
>> point of order. This has nothing to do
with the uh, DDA budget. Mr. Chairman,
>> point of order taken. We're not
discussing an audit or discussing the
DDA budget and your time is up, Mr.
Miller. Thank you for your comments.
>> Any further online
comments.
Any further comments or questions from
the committee?
Can I get a motion?
Councilman White, did you have something
further to say?
>> I did not, Mr. Chair. I'm sorry. I
forgot to lower my hand.
>> Can I get a motion?
Um, Mr. Chairman, I move to adopt.
>> Second.
>> It's been moved by Councilman Wolf,
second by Councilman White. Any further
comments or discussion? Councilman
Moody.
>> All right. Thank you, Mr. Chairman.
Through you. Um,
yeah, I'm looking through this. I really
do think the sidewalks and the bricks
and the curves need to be the first
priority. I would have liked to have
seen a lot more to that. I mean, if
there were changes, communications plan
was still $60,000 and maybe sidewalk
mash program is $130,000
and there was some graffiti removal
there with the program or even just
coming out of the budget I before this.
But because of that, I'm going to be a
no vote for today. I really want to see
those changes there because I we got to
get back to the basics. Uh ladies and
gentlemen, tourists are going to be
coming. first thing they see is our
sidewalks and seeing if there's anger
fee there, they're going to notice it.
So, I really do think we need to adjust
those numbers there. Thank you.
>> And we'll have those opportunities in
the budget to make those amendments and
I know those issues are very important
to everyone on the council. Uh with
that, all in favor signify by saying I.
>> I.
>> All opposed.
Just seeing that that uh is an
affirmative. The recommendation of the
finance committee will be to adopt at
the next meeting of the governing body.
Next item
>> number 30 resolution amending city
provided health insurance related
benefits for specified permanent
part-time city employees and members of
the city council of the city of
Cheyenne.
>> Staff report.
>> Good afternoon colleagues. Um Dr.
Michelle Aldrich from city council ward
3. Um, I am pleased to be able to
sponsor this resolution. I wanted to
give you some background on this
resolution. Um, in talking with our um,
city staff and looking for when it first
became um, a possibility for our um,
council members to receive insurance
benefits. Um, that goes back to I
believe now we've determined 1995.
Um, this resolution before you would
allow our part-time employees who work
uh have been working part-time,
averaging between 20 and 30 hours a week
for at least three years, to be able to
have the same benefits that the council
has uh had voted previously in 1995 to
give themselves, which is access to our
um city health insurance and benefits.
Um many of you may know or may not know
that um
there have been really two classes if
you will of um duality here with um city
council members um who actually um when
we went into a self- insurance pool had
not been listed as their own
classification which I believe now has
been corrected for as of May 1st. Um
this would go into effect with the
election um of C of council members in
2028.
Well, they would be elected in 27 or 26,
but they would go in actually into
effect in 27. Um they'll be elected in
26 into effect on 27. And so that anyone
who is currently able to access
insurance benefits on the council uh
would not be impacted by this
resolution.
Um, this resolution would allow council
members um, in the future and our
part-time city employees, of which I
believe we've identified 19 now, to be
able to access insurance benefits
equally. Um, to give you an idea, we
have currently four council members who
access our health insurance benefits as
a city. We are probably not the poster
children for um, bringing down the risk
of that uh, insurance pool just because
of our demographic. um with our youngest
member being just over 40. So um we
probably have not done them a lot of
favors of being part of the city
employee insurance pool. It would allow
uh city council members in the future to
participate in this pool um but they
would be responsible for paying not only
their monthly um insurance amount which
they currently are paying which I
understand is about $23 per month uh for
a family policy. Um, but there is an
$1,800 amount that the city is currently
paying for each of the council members
who exercises the right to participate
in the city benefit program. Um, this
would allow city council members and our
part-time employees to participate in
that insurance program uh by paying not
only the $200 amount that would be their
um enrollment amount normally, but also
the amount that the city's currently
incurring on their behalf. Um when you
look at um the number of hours,
I would say that there are days when
many of us on council or in many weeks
that we put in 20 to 30 hours. Um
especially if you have long committee
meetings or meetings that go until
midnight. Um but I would say that we
probably are not working any more hours
than our uh regular part-time employees
are. Um, and so I believe that with this
resolution, we um bring into the public
arena the conversation about um benefits
for city council members. We get that um
reaffirmed and on the record um since we
weren't um part of that when we went to
the self- insurance pool and we also
allow the same benefit to our part-time
employees that we've been affording our
council members over the the last um 31
years. So, I would encourage you to
support this. Um, I believe that
benefits is a big piece of retention for
our um part-time employees and our city
employees. Um, I've heard anecdotal
stories that we have county employees
who actually come to the city because we
um offer such a great benefit package at
such a low cost. And um I believe that
it's important to get this taken care of
now so that those who are filing for
office on when it opens in May uh we'll
know uh with some certainty whether
they're going to have insurance benefits
access or not. Um while it may um
encourage some people to run if they
know they're going to have access to
benefits even if they're having to pay
for them. Um it probably quite honestly
to most people is an unknown benefit.
Um, in addition to the stipen that
council members receive, um, and
recognizing that for some of our council
members, the $2,000 that we receive as a
stipen would be completely consumed by a
a family policy, um, if we were to make
sure that council members had benefits
at no expense to the city. So, um, I
think it's important for us to get this
taken care of before the new filing
deadline. I'd like to in um invite you
to ask any questions you have of Mr. Haw
um our treasurer Robin Lockman um and
David Hopkinson have been the group that
I've been working with on this as well
as co-sponsor Councilman Moody. So with
that uh we'll all stand for questions.
>> Any comments or questions from the
committee for Dr. Aldrich?
Any questions for Director Hos, our city
attorney
or city treasurer?
Uh, Director Hos,
come on. What's
the average uh take-home pay for? Well,
let's go gross. What's the average gross
salary for our those 19 part-time
employees?
>> Through you, Mr. Chair. Darren ask human
resources.
Of of those 19 that average about 20
hours or more a week, I I don't have a
calculator, but 20 hours you our average
pay for part-time is about 19 bucks an
hour.
>> And then with this, they would be paying
close to 2,000.
>> Yeah. That the 2000, Mr. share the 2,000
that's for the that's for employee and
spouse if it's family it's higher if
it's just employee only it would be a
little bit less okay
um that's the only question I have
any other comments or questions from the
committee to the directors
or sponsors
we'll go to public comment in the
public comment online.
>> Um, Mr. Chairman, I do have Councilman
Crrave with us. Hand raised.
>> President Crave, go ahead.
>> Thank you, Mr. Chairman. Can you hear
me?
>> Yeah.
>> Very good. Mr. Chairman, I have just a
few notes I'd like to share with you.
Um, Councilman Aldrich has prepared a
resolution where she tries to compare
the job of a city councilman to a
permanent part-time employee. This is
inaccurate for many reasons. Uh, I don't
know about you, but uh, I did not fill
out a job application. I was not
interviewed by HR or anyone else. I did
not complete onboarding, and I do not
have a manager or a boss. The mayor
cannot fire me, discipline me, sanction
my stipen, or document a personnel file.
Councilmen are not employees. Councilmen
are the legislative body for the city of
Cheyenne. Councilmen are elected
officials whose role in government
primarily by laws and rules applicable
to elected officials, including which
include voting, legislation, ethics, and
open meeting rules. not the same HR
employee workplace structure as a
part-time employee. Our stipens are not
set by statute or correction. Our
stipens are set by statute, not
developed through human resource
surveys.
Councilmen do not have employee benefits
or protections such as unemployment,
workers comp, paid time off, holiday
pay, sick leave, etc. Since at least
1988, according to Dr. Renie who's our
senior member councilmen have been
eligible to participate in the various
insurance programs offered by the city
but this is not specific just to the
city of Cheyenne. Our local county
commissioners and other elected
officials also have the opportunity to
purchase health insurance.
Clearly, councilmen and permanent
part-time employees have different
employer employee structures and should
not be compared. Even if this resolution
finds favor, as Dr. Aldrich recently
pointed out, neither permanent part-time
employees nor council members receive
enough compensation to participate in
the program, as described in her third
further resolved paragraph.
For these reasons and others, I
encourage you to give this resolution
the quick death sentence it deserves. I
expect the co-sponsor to move to approve
this. I encourage the rest of the body
not to second the motion. Thank you.
Any further public comment online?
Seeing none, we come back to the
committee. Um any comments or questions
before I ask for a motion?
Can I get a motion?
>> Uh, Mr. Chairman, I move to adopt.
>> There a second.
Is there a second?
Hearing none. That motion
fails.
Due to lack of a second, there will be
no recommendation from the finance
committee at the next meeting of the
governing body. Next item.
Number 31D, purchase and sale agreement
between the city of Cheyenne and Nick
and April Feruli,
Co Naz Nas Investment Group LLC for
property located at 803 West 16th
Street, 1510 Reed Avenue, 1508 Reed
Avenue, and 1506 Reed Avenue for
greenway and compliance use.
>> Staff report. Uh chair chairman and
committee members Jean Shrednick parks
and greenway planner. Um the purpose of
this agreement is to purchase property
for the downtown greenway connector and
provide a muchneeded 2500 square f foot
storage building and other storage areas
for the compliance department. The
downtown greenway connector has been
contemplated for many years and will
allow the pump house open space area
trail to connect to the existing trails
from Martin Luther King Park and the
Crow Creek Trail to the downtown area.
The appraised value of the property is
$650,000.
Um the funding will come from $300,000
from the 2021 six penny for greenway
expansion and $350,000 in funding will
come from general fund reserves. Um
$8,200 has been paid out of the greenway
account already for the appraisal and
the phase one environmental assessment.
Um happy to show you those documents if
everyone is interested. Um, if approved
by council, the closing will take place
in the mayor's office on May uh May 1st,
2026.
I'd be happy to answer any questions you
have,
>> comments or questions from the committee
to staff.
We'll go to public comment in the room.
Welcome, Councilman.
>> Thank you, Mr. Chairman. Um,
this is an important connection, uh, an
important purchase in two ways. I'm sure
we're all aware of the uh stub, I guess
you could call it, of the path coming up
from Ames Avenue and the greenway there
partially through this uh the city-owned
property there by the pump house. So,
the question of getting that path up to
Lincoln Way and connecting up that
three-way
connection to the uh Greenway to
downtown is really a great opportunity.
I'm glad this property happened to come
up to sale so that we could do this. But
secondarily, uh, Mr. Chairman and
members of the committee is the
importance of that building and its use
by the compliance department.
I sure we all remember the compliance
report and that kind of effort that that
department puts in in uh issues of
neglect
uh
transient camps that are very difficult
to uh clean up and keep clean. So this
will really offer them an opportunity to
gather their equipment and their staff
in one place and be able to do that. So,
uh, this particular purchase has
multiple benefits and I think that, uh,
it's one of the really most important
things that we have before us is
connecting that greenway to downtown.
We have almost 50 miles of greenway
throughout the city. People use it. I
bet they're out there today quite a bit.
And uh so uh and I've been assume you
have been questioned quite a bit about
how are we going to take this to the
next step. It's been it's been years.
Well, we have to acquire the property.
So, I urge you to uh uh vote yes on this
and so that we can take it Monday night
and actually accomplish a very important
piece of the long-term benefit that the
greenway does bring to Cheyenne and will
bring to downtown.
Thank you.
>> Anyone on the committee have any
questions for Councilman Labour?
Mr. Chairman,
>> go ahead, Councilman Wolf.
>> Thank you, Mr. Chairman. Through you,
um, thank you, Mr. Lelay. Um, you were
the one who spotted this opportunity,
and I congratulate you for that and
bringing it to the attention of the um
city and and um the mayor and and this
council. Um and um I guess you might if
you have a have another minute just sort
of describe how you envision this all
this this critical juncture fitting into
the 15th Street uh corridor and also the
pathway up to the base.
Well, it's a very unique and uh very
challenging project. I I conceive it as
the uh 15th or the Reed corridor that
we're acting on right now coming down
from nearby here at 23rd Street down
eventually to Lincoln Way and then the
path uh coming up from Ames Avenue
coming up and connecting there and then
uh the benefit then and I'd be glad to
show any of the members of the plans
that or the maps that we have. Um you
actually have the opportunity on 15th
Street to go from right there at uh that
corner all the way down and all the way
to Holiday Park partially a concrete
path and then from the depot to Holiday
Park as a shared roadway with a bike
lane. So, it's really a tremendous
opportunity and one that uh I I do want
to emphasize one element here. Uh it's
it's it's
a price we have to that we have to pay
for that property.
But throughout the entire development of
the greenway system, which has gone on
now for
25 years, there's never been a case of
the city of Cheyenne engaging in uh
condemnation
for any property. No, no eminent domain.
Never happened. And many, many property
owners have uh helped us out with uh
either easements or granting the
property. So that context I think is
important here in that uh we we are uh
really progressing with a very difficult
but important project that uh I believe
will be just like the rest of the
greenway and some of the controversies
we had uh getting started with the
overpass and the underpass and so it's a
big step and uh I hope that answers your
question.
Thank you.
>> Thank you.
>> Any further public comment in the room?
>> Hello, Sophia Mays, executive director
of the DDA. Again, uh I would like to be
to comment in favor of this purchase.
This is part of um as Councilman Lelay
Warren mentioned part of that greenway
connection uh in downtown the DDA plan
of development that was adopted by the
governing body in early 2024 as a public
planning document for all of downtown.
Um the Reed Rail corridor, 15th Street,
Pump House Park, all of that uh
incorporate catalyst projects to spur
economic development and economic growth
downtown. Um, we are seeing a lot of
interest specifically in residential
units in downtown and this will be an
amenity connecting that greenway will be
an incredible amenity to produce more of
those residential units. Our current um
believe the last numbers that I have
were our daytime population is around
8,500 and our actual population is about
8 850. So we have about 10% um
residential population a healthy mix is
about 25%.
spurring or investing in amenities like
this uh to spur residential um
properties in downtown will be critical
not only for the the health and wellness
of those residents uh but also when they
live downtown they spend their money
downtown it's critical to business to
walkability and to the health of the the
downtown district. Thank you.
>> Any further public comment in the room?
Any public comment online?
>> Mr. Miller, you can unmute yourself.
>> I'm gonna try to
>> I'm going to try to stick to uh things
pretty tight here for you guys at this
time. Can you hear me?
>> Yes.
>> Um Mr. Chairman, members of the finance
committee, Charles Miller, I'm speaking
strictly to item 31D. That's where we're
at. Correct.
>> Correct. Um the purchase and sale
agreement for the Reed Avenue and West
16th Street properties.
>> Correct.
>> Oh, okay. Um I'm asking this committee
to reject this contract based on its
appropriation source. Um according to
the supporting documents, the city is
executing a $650,000
buyout from is it NAS investment group?
>> Correct. Um and that's with a
significant portion drawn directly from
the general fund. Um in a finance
committee capacity, we must distinguish
between essential expenditures and
discretionary acquisitions. The general
fund is intended for core municipal
operations and emergency reserves, not
largecale discretionary real estate
purchases. Draining $650,000
for a discretionary acquisition listed
here for greenway use represents a
material depletion of operating
liquidity at a time when the city is
facing unbudgeted infrastructure
liabilities elsewhere. You cannot
credibly claim that the general fund is
too strained to properly fund core
municipal upkeep while simultaneously
using that same fund to act as a
commercial real estate purchaser on Reed
Avenue. I urge a no vote on this spec
this specific expenditure to protect the
city's primary operating reserves. Thank
you, Mr. Chairman.
>> Thank you for your comments. Any further
comments online? Any
comments or questions from the
committee?
>> Mr. Chair,
>> Councilman White,
>> just want to point out based on the uh
comments that we just heard that
$300,000 of the $650,000
uh before us on this item is coming from
2021 six penny overage funds. So, the
fact that the entire 650 uh 650,000 is
coming from uh the general fund is
inaccurate. Thank you,
>> Councilman Moody.
>> Uh thank you, Mr. Chair. I concur with
my colleague from Ward One and also two,
it's for storage areas for the
compliance department. Um I just wanted
to ask if uh Mr. Fountain can uh just uh
come up and uh tell the public how this
would be very beneficial for the
compliance department.
>> Welcome director.
>> Thank you Mr. Chairman through you too
Mr. Moody to answer the question. Um we
have a lot of stuff scattered throughout
the city. We don't never had our own uh
location to post our vehicles to post
our supplies um to put our tools. We
have generators. is we have a lot of
power tools, cords, etc. And so, um, my
colleagues are gracious enough to allow
us to store some things in closets here
and some parking garage closets. We have
some over at the public works facility.
We have some over at the parks building.
Um, it's it's scattered everywhere. Um,
but makes it difficult because when we
have to go out and do a cleanup, you
have to run over here and get this. A
good example is if we use the utility
trailer that we have, we have to unload
certain items um, so that we can load
new items in to go to a new location.
depending on what we have going. So, for
us, it'd be a really nice opportunity uh
to locate all of the um tools that have
been acquired and equipment has been
acquired by the taxpayers um to have it
all in one spot, keep a close eye on the
inventory and understand what we have.
>> Thank you so much. That was very
helpful,
>> Councilman Wolf.
>> Uh thank you, Mr. Chairman. Uh through
you, um thank you, Mr. Fountainant and
uh on behalf of the city, we really
appreciate all the work that you do on a
on a daily basis to uh attend to the
many responsibilities you have. Um have
you had an opportunity to look at this
building and see whether or not you're
going to need any upgrades to it or
improvements, repairs, things like that?
>> Mr. Chairman, through you to Councilman
Wolf, we're just excited. we we're not
the kind of people that need a lot of
fancy things. So, for us, it's it's it's
pretty darn nice. And um we don't
forecast or see anything right now that
we're currently currently going to need
other than just having that opportunity
to have a place finally is much
appreciated. And we thank this council.
Um I also want to recognize my staff
though. You you thanked me and I I have
to thank my staff. I have some very
dedicated people um that care a lot
about this community and care a lot
about one city, one standard. And so, I
want to thank you, but I'll also pass
that along.
Any further comments or questions from
the committee?
>> Can I get a motion?
>> Mr. Chairman, I move to approve an
amount not to exceed $650,000.
>> Second.
>> It's been moved by Councilman Moody,
second by Councilman Wolf. Any further
comments or discussion?
All in favor signify by saying I.
>> I. Seeing there's none oppo opposed that
the recommendation of the finance
committee at the next meeting of the
governing body will be to approve. Next
item
>> number 31E drainage easement agreement
between the city of Cheyenne and
Christopher Cost and Deborah Elost
trustees of the postrevocable trust for
a recently constructed storm water
detention pond.
>> Staff report.
>> Good afternoon. Aaron Gates staff
engineer. Uh this item is a drainage
easement agreement for a newly
constructed facility generally north of
Del Range and east of Ridge Road
commonly known as Brakes Plus. This item
is re been reviewed by staff. The
property owner will be responsible for
the operation and maintenance of the
detention pond but this sement agreement
does allow city access for emergency
situations of the pond. I stand for any
questions.
Any questions for from the committee to
staff?
Councilman Moody, I mean, Councilman
Wolf.
>> Fine, M. Moody. Did you?
>> No. Okay. Um, thank you and thank you
for your work on this. Um, we have these
kinds of agreements with with other
owners of of detention uh facilities.
Isn't that true,
>> Chairman? Through you uh to Councilman
Wolf. Yes, we are working on this. This
also limits um a developer's ability to
maybe construct other things in the
future. So we ensure that detention is
properly taken care of in the future.
>> Any further questions for staff?
>> Okay, we'll go to public comment in the
room
and see none. Any public comment online?
Seeing none. Can I get a motion?
>> Uh, Mr. Chairman, I move to approve.
>> Second.
>> Been moved by Councilman Wolf. Second by
Councilman Moody. Any further comments
or questions?
None. All in favor signify by saying I.
>> I.
>> Again, that's unanimous decision. The
recommendation of the finance committee
will be to approve at the next meeting
of the governing body. Next item
>> number 31F, professional services
agreement between the city of Cheyenne
and WM Recycle America LLC for recycling
services for the city of Cheyenne
Sanitation Division.
>> Good afternoon, Craig Lavoy uh public
works. This contract is with uh Waste
Management Recycling of America and they
are the ones that process and handle our
single stream recycling. We have a
three-year contract for a cost not to
succe exceed 750,000. So that's about
$250,000 a year not to exceed. And I
recommend approval. And I'll stand for
questions.
>> Questions from the committee for staff.
Looks like you're getting off easy, Mr.
Little.
We'll go to public comment.
Public comment in the room.
Public comment online.
Come back to the committee.
Oh.
can go ahead and speak.
>> Go ahead, Mr. Miller.
>> Um, yes. Hi, this is Charles Miller. Can
you hear me?
>> We can.
>> Um, is this item number uh 31F?
>> Yes, it is.
>> And it's the $750,000
recycling contract.
>> Yes, it is.
Um, members of the committee, I'm
speaking strictly to the professional
services agreement with WM Recycle
America LLC. Uh, did I get the company
name right there?
>> Yes.
>> Um, I'm I'm asking the committee to
scrutinize this specific contract based
on its financial footprint. According to
your supporting documents, this
agreement commits $750,000
over a three-year term drawn entirely
from the solid waste fund. My objection
is purely financial. 3/4 of a million to
an outsourced professional service
services contract requires absolute
justification at a time when the city is
financially strained. The taxpayers
expect our utility and sanitation funds
to be tightly managed for core physical
operations, not outsourced for massive
service contracts. I urge the committee
to review whether this $750,000
expenditure represents the most
efficient use of the solid waste fund
and I ask for a no vote. Thank you.
>> Thank you for your comments, sir. Any
further comments on online?
bring it back to the committee for a
motion.
>> Uh Mr. Chairman, before for make the
motion, can I just ask for clarification
uh from staff? Um
is this uh this type of contract this
happens every three years so often? Is
that correct?
>> You chairman. Yes, this has been going
on for we do three-year contracts, but
it's been for 10, 15 years. Hey,
>> thank you.
Can I get a motion?
>> Uh, yes, Mr. Chairman. Um, I um
move to approve an amount not to exceed
$750,000
for the term of three years.
>> Second.
>> It's been moved by Councilman Wolf,
second by Councilman White. Any further
discussion from the committee?
All in favor signify by saying I.
Any opposed?
No. But I didn't hear one for Jeff.
Okay.
Hearing that motion is unanimous. The
recommendation of the finance committee
will be to approve at the next meeting
of the governing body. Next item,
please.
>> Number 31G. grant agreement between the
city of Cheyenne and the US Department
of Transportation, Federal Transit
Administration for a section 5339B
competitive and section 5339
formula grant for the Cheyenne Transit
Facility renovation at 1800 Westland
Road.
>> Staff report.
>> Uh good afternoon uh chair. My name is
Aaron Johnson. from the Cheyenne Transit
Program transit administrator. Um, this
is a uh formula FTA 51 5339 grant uh
that was applied for in May of 2025 that
was due in July of 2025 and we were
notified of award um in November of 2025
and um as stated this is for the uh
Westland uh Cheyenne Transit Facility uh
building.
Any comments or questions from the
committee to staff? Councilman Moody.
>> Thank you, Mr. Chairman. Three. Uh,
thank you, Miss Johnson. Uh, just for
the public to know, this has been going
on since the 80s. I mean, can do you
just want to clarify that for the public
to understand how this is important for
our community?
>> Uh, chair, Mr. Moody, um, from the 80s,
are you referring to the, uh, purchase
of the building, renovation of the
building?
Oh,
>> I'm referring to this whole program for
for this, correct?
>> Yes. So, this is for the um the new
Cheyenne Transit facility that is
located at 1800 Westland Road. Uh that
was purchased back in 2022 uh with
federal funds. Um at that time, the
director had not been able to secure the
funding uh before her departure um from
the city and at it was kind of at a
standstill. So, for a while, yes.
Okay.
Any uh other comments or questions from
the committee staff?
Thank you. We'll go to public comment in
the room.
See none. Any public comment online?
>> Mr. Miller, you should be able to unmute
yourself.
>> Um yes. Hi. Can you hear me?
>> Yeah.
Um, members of the committee, I'm
speaking,
excuse me, I'm speaking strictly to the
text of the grant agreements in items
31G and 31H. Is that correct?
>> Only 31G.
>> Oh. Oh. Well, um
uh regarding item 31G,
um the document explicitly states,
quote, the local match is from the
city's general fund. Is is that correct,
>> Chair throughu? That is correct. There
is a um 8020 uh federal funding uh ratio
for this this match.
>> Oh, okay. Um, and so you're committing
an additional $828,720
straight out of the general fund to
renovate a transit facility today,
>> chair, through you, that is correct.
>> Um, okay. Um
well, I I definitely urge a no vote. Um
uh because
uh awarding pre
uh basically while while you guys are
claiming insolveny on physical
infrastructure,
um it's it's fiscally irresponsible
um to retroactively rubber stamp um
these expenditures. That's all I have
for now. Thank you.
>> Thank you for your comments, sir. Any
further comments online?
Seeing none, I'll bring it back to the
committee. Any comments or are you ready
to give me a motion?
>> Uh, Mr. Chairman, I move to approve an
amount of uh 4,143,600.
>> Second.
It's been moved by Councilman Moody and
seconded by both Councilman Wolf and
White.
Any further discussion?
>> I chairman.
>> Councilman Moody.
>> Yep. Thanks. Turn it through. Um just
for the public to know that uh the city
matches $800,2800$800,828,728.
And again, this has been going on for
quite a while. We need to refurbish the
building. It's our duty as a government
for transportation, basic function of
government, and then the federal
government is going to provide over $3
million. So, this is actually a good
thing. Again, it's our duty with regards
to basic transportation, especially for
those that can't afford basic
transportation. Thank you, Mr. Chairman.
>> Councilman Wolf.
>> Uh, thank you, Mr. Chairman. Through
you, I agree wholeheartedly with
Councilman Moody's comments. I I would
also like to assure the public that the
city is not insolvent uh and we're not
insolvent in any respect. Insolveny from
a legal perspective is a very
significant
uh undertaking and uh and it's
absolutely no truth to that statement.
So thank you Miss Johnson for all your
work on this. This is an important
aspect of the overall transit system
which um I think is a model for uh how
these um systems ought to be operated.
>> Thank you chairman.
>> Councilman.
>> Well said by both of you.
All in favor signify by saying I.
>> I.
>> Seeing there's none opposed. The
recommendation of the finance committee
will be to approve at the next meeting
of the governing body. Next item
>> number 31H. grant agreement between the
city of Cheyenne and the US Department
of Transportation, Federal Transit
Administration for a section 5307
operating assistance, ADA paratransit
operating assistance, PM vehicles
facilities, and a capital grant for the
Cheyenne Transit System Program.
>> Staff report.
>> Thank you, Mr. Chair. Aaron Johnson
again, Cheyenne Transit Program, transit
administrator. Um this is a grant
agreement from the FTA for our 5307
operating funds. This is program income
to the city. Uh these uh this income
cover driver salaries, capital projects,
small capital projects, and operating
costs.
>> Any questions for staff from the
committee?
>> Oh, just a comment, Mr. Chairman.
>> Thank you, Miss Johnson. I the question
was meant for this one, so I do
apologize. That was my fault thinking
ahead, but just for the public to know,
this was going on for decades. So, we're
just renewing it.
>> Correct. Right.
>> Yes, that is correct.
>> All right, we'll go to public comment in
the room.
See none. Public comment online.
Seeing none, we'll come back to the
committee. Any further comments from the
committee?
Can I get a motion?
>> Um, Mr. Chairman, I move to approve in
the amount of 3,291,390.
Second.
>> It's been moved by Councilman Wolf,
second by Councilman Moody. Any further
comments or questions?
>> Just a clarification.
>> Councilman Moody, go ahead.
>> Uh, thank you. And again, uh, ladies and
gentlemen, we've been doing this again,
I've been told, since the 1980s. This is
really, this is nothing new. So again,
you know, it was meant for the previous
one. And again, there is a match by the
federal government. Our share is
1,262,775,
but again, we've been doing this for
decades, so nothing new. Thank you.
>> All those in favor signify by saying I.
I
>> and there's none opposed. The
recommendation of the finance committee
will be to approve at the next meeting
of the governing body. Next item
>> number 32B contract modification number
two to contract number 7955 between the
city of Cheyenne and Tri Hydro
Corporation for landfill mapping and
surveying services.
>> Staff report.
Good afternoon. Sam Patrini, public
works landfield manager.
Um this is a modification to the
existing contract 79 55 with Triad
Corporation to provide the landfill with
surveying um mapping services and u
bears a cost of $49,08
and will be sp um paid through the solid
waste fund. And I'm here for any
question. Any questions or comments from
the committee for staff?
>> M Mr. Chairman. Um
>> go ahead, Councilman Wolf.
>> Thank you through you. Um thank you very
much. Um
can you just tell us a little bit about
this this surveying and mapping is I
mean that's an absolutely essential
feature of operating this landfill,
isn't it? um because of all the
reporting requirements um that you have
uh and also to know obviously uh on on a
regular basis sort of what your capacity
is what's being used.
>> Uh chairman for you uh yes uh council
member Wolf that's absolutely correct.
This is essential for our operations uh
also for our uh annual reporting that we
do with uh with the EQ uh with the
department of environmental quality with
the state of Wyoming. Um we do it
through uh it's very interesting because
we're modernizing we're doing it through
uh drone flights. So it's uh uh the
product is very is very good and it
after this is the third year is is
getting very accurate. Um I just
submitted our annual report to uh to the
state so it's public record and I can
say we have approximately 55 years at
least in MSW in municipal solid waste
and about 16 years in the um
construction demolition. So, uh, we're
we're doing pretty good on that end.
Thank you.
>> Thank you. Any, uh, further questions
for staff?
Seeing none, we'll go to public comment
in the room.
Any public comment online?
Seeing none. Excuse
me.
>> Mr. Miller,
>> can you hear me?
>> Go ahead.
>> Um, Miss, can you hear me?
>> Yes, we can.
>> Mr. Chairman, members of the finance
committee, Charles Miller,
I'm speaking strictly on the um the
Trihydro Corporation contract um for
landfill monitoring. Is that correct?
>> Correct. Um, my objection is fiscal. Uh,
we're approving hundreds of thousands
for environmental monitoring of legacy
landfill liabilities at HappyJack, which
is appropriate.
Um however the final the finance
committee has not been with a cost
comparison of legacy waste monitoring
versus um active wastewater monitoring
costs elsewhere in the budget. Um maybe
I'm maybe I'm wrong there. Correct me if
I'm wrong. Um uh but also uh
documentation showing that landfill
groundwater monitoring is the highest
priority environmental liability facing
the city right now. Um, at a time when
the city faces multiple unbudgeted
environmental compliance costs across
departments, I urge a no vote until
staff provides a prioritized
environmental liability cost matrix that
justifies this expenditure above
competing needs. The question for
finance is simple. Is HappyJack landfill
monitoring more urgent than other
environmental obligations? Without that
analysis, this is an unprioritized
expenditure. Thank you, Mr. Chairman.
>> Thank you for your comments.
Any further comments online?
We'll bring it back to the committee for
any comments or questions.
Seeing none, can I get a motion?
>> Uh, Mr. Chairman, I move to approve an
amount not to exceed $49,08
for one year.
>> It's been moved by Councilman Moody,
second by Councilman Wolf. Any further
comments?
>> I do, Mr. Chairman.
>> Councilman Moody, go ahead.
>> Uh, thank thank you, Mr. Chairman,
through you. Um, this is very important.
You know, this is basic again basics
what we are responsible to for our
constituents. It's mapping it out. I
think it's very important especially for
a landfill. And again, all it is is
mapping it out. So this is very vital so
that way we can use our landfills
effectively. Thank you Mr. Chairman.
>> Thank you.
>> All those in favor signify by saying I.
>> I.
>> Seeing that there's none opposed. The
recommendation of the finance committee
will be to approve at the next meeting
of the governing body. Next item
>> number 32 C. Contract modification
number one to contract number 8259
between the city of Cheyenne and Labs
Inc. for transit paratransit dispatch
system and a new fixed route tracking
system
>> staff report.
>> Um
sorry uh Aaron Johnson Shyen transit
program um chair through you to the
council or to the committee. Uh this is
a modification to our current spare
contract. Sparab is um a company that we
currently operate with for our
paratransit tracking uh wrership
tracking um and all of the things uh
that are involved with that. Um our uh
paratransit app that riders are
encouraged to use for uh scheduling
their trips as well as um the AI side of
it. Uh what we are asking for today is
um we have been looking for a new fixed
route uh piece to this. Uh we currently
do not track our fixed route buses. Um
so the public is not aware of time
frames of when they're going to arrive
at stops, where they're at, and what the
um location where they're at where their
locations are throughout their uh trips.
Um,
Spray Labs was chosen out of five
candidates uh due to the fact that we do
have an operating contract with them
currently and uh we are very satisfied
with uh their dashboards and how they um
do our writership. So that is uh the
annual current contract is uh $54,000525
uh with an increase every year 5%
increase. Uh what this contract will add
to is an additional uh $78,000 for a
grand total of $134,711.
Um again with a 5% increase on an annual
basis. Um and this is also paid for out
of our operating funds.
>> Any questions for staff from the
committee?
>> Seeing none, we'll go to public comment
in the room.
public comment online.
Seeing none back to the committee
is
Mr. Miller, do you have a comment on
this item?
>> Mr. Miller, you can go ahead and unmute
yourself.
>> Can you hear me? We can hear you.
>> Um, this is the item, uh, Charles
Miller, uh, members of the committee,
uh, this is item number 32C. Is that
correct?
>> Correct.
>> Okay. Um,
excuse me. Um, I'm speaking strictly to
item 32C. It's the spare labs contract
modification for the paratransit
dispatch and fixed route tracking
system.
Um
my objection is based on fiscal
efficiency and per rider subsidy risks
today. You are authorizing a $78,000
addition. Is that correct?
>> Correct.
um pushing this single route management
software contract to over what is it 140
$134,000
>> correct?
>> Um uh well with that being said uh you
guys are doing this uh this committee is
being asked to approve this rather uh
without a verified utility to cost
matrix. Um is that correct?
not correct.
>> Um so you guys uh have received um a
recent audited ridership data comparing
passenger miles to the cost per mile and
a pre and post implementation return on
investment projection for this specified
software. Um and then a final uh current
per rider cost data comparing
microtransit to fixed route services.
>> Correct.
Oh, so so you guys you guys have all
three of those things.
>> Sarah through you that is accessible.
Yes.
>> Yeah. Because we do want people to be
able to get to work and groceries,
things like that that don't have
transportation.
>> But you guys have this uh these these
documents the
that I just specified.
>> That is correct. So, okay. Um, well
then, uh, I'm going to go ahead and, uh,
um, uh, you know, close my comment on
this one. Thank you.
>> Thank you, sir. We come back to the
committee for any comments,
>> Councilman Moody.
>> Mr. Chairman, I move to uh move to
approve an amount not to exceed $78,000.
It's been moved by Councilman Moody,
second by Councilman White. Any further
comments?
>> Just real quick, Mr.
>> Councilman Moody.
>> Thank you, Mr. Chairman. Through you, I
just uh realize for the public, this is
going to improve efficiency and it's
important for people know the fixed
route, you know, what the times are and
that, especially if they're on a very
tight schedule. You know, a lot of
municipalities have this, so it's no
different than any of them. Thank you.
Okay. All those in favor signify by
saying I.
>> I.
>> And that that vote is unanimous. The
recommendation of the finance committee
will be to approve at the next meeting
of the governing body. Next item
>> number 33B, consideration of bid number
S-20-26
for a contract between the city of
Cheyenne and Construction Incorporated
for the Cheyenne Botanic Gardens Smith
Education Agricultural and Trial Eat
Garden
>> staff report. Mr. Chair, Jason Sanchez,
Community Recreation and Events. Uh
before you and for your consideration is
a bid to construct an eat garden which
was part of our 2024 master plan for
Botanic Gardens. Um we are the the
community wreck and events department
will assist with construction management
and taking care of paying contractor
invoices. However, we are very blessed
to have a partnership with the friends
of the botanic garden who are funding
this project 100%.
With me in attendance today is the
architect Craig Russell, our president
of the botanic our friends of the
botanic garden Randy Buyers and our
botanic garden manager Aaron Summers.
And we al would stand by for questions.
>> Any questions for staff? Councilman
Moody.
>> Thank you. Thank you, Mr. Sanchez. Would
you say this is very vital with more
tourism for the Botanic Gardens?
>> Mr. Chair through you. Absolutely.
>> Yeah,
>> Mr. Chair, Councilman White,
>> just a comment. the Botanic Gardens
never ceases to amaze me and just the
work that the their foundation uh the
friends of the Botanic Gardens all the
work that they do throughout the year.
They're they're good financial stewards
of their their monies as evidenced here
being able to fund this uh project from
within. Um so just kudos to all
involved. It it's truly one of the crown
jewels of our community.
>> Yes, it is.
Council lady.
>> Yep. Thank you. Yeah, I want to echo
what my colleague once said and for the
public. If you look at the bids here,
we're using they're using $854,000
and the Ryman the most expensive was
$1,165,000.
So, they are good stewards of money.
Thank you.
>> Okay, we'll go to public comment in the
room. Mr. buyers. Welcome.
>> Thank you, Mr. Chair. Randy Buyers, as
uh introduced by Jason, I am privileged
to be the chair of the Friends of the
Cheyenne Botanic Gardens Board. I'm
going to pass out and I'll apologize to
Councilman White since he's online. Um
just a packet of some renderings
renderings that show the intended uh
development of the eat garden. As uh
director Sanchez mentioned um the
friends of the Cheyenne Botanic Gardens
has committed funding of this contract.
We appreciate the partnership with the
city and the assistance of city staff
for this project. The Eat Garden, which
is, as uh Jason mentioned, part of the
overall master plan for the Botanic
Gardens, is really an immersive and
dynamic space in an currently
underutilized area of the gardens. um
plan to allow visitors to see and take
part in demonstration gardens
highlighting um lowmaintenance, drought
tolerant, locally adapted vegetables,
flour, and and uh fruit uh for use here
in Cheyenne
and um that are specifically oriented
towards our climate and our location. Um
this is really a milestone for the board
and the staff at Cheyenne Botanic
Gardens. This project has been
envisioned and planned for for a very
long time and we are very blessed uh
through the generous donations of uh a
number of uh parties here in Cheyenne,
quite a number of parties to be able to
fully fund this project through the
friends. This is of at no cost to the
city. Um,
we are uh the the foundation is a
nonprofit foundation whose mission is to
support the Cheyenne Botanic Gardens and
the High Plains Arboritum. And we're
proud to work alongside the staff in
bringing these kind of improvements
um to both the gardens and the
arboritum. And uh as I think council
will echo, we believe that the Botanic
Gardens and the High Plains Arboritum
are two of the uh really important
cultural and civic jewels of our
community and I would be glad to answer
any questions.
>> Councilman Moody.
>> Y uh thank you sir. Uh would you echo
Mr. the question asked Mr. Sanchez? Is
this very important from a tourism
perspective to increase uh people
visiting?
>> Mr. Chair, through you um Councilman
Moody, the Botanic Gardens as a tourist
destination within the city or tourist
draw within the city is one of the most
significant
um uh destinations for visitors to our
city. Over 70 countries a year, 70,000
visitors. Um, with the other development
of Cheyenne Frontier Days in the park,
um, I think you're going to see all of
that increase. Uh the master plan that
that director Sanchez alluded to gives
us direction for the next number of
years regarding further enhancement and
development of the grounds and with the
goal of improving the already really
outstanding
uh offerings from Botanic Garden staff
uh for the citizens and for visitors to
our city.
>> Thank you so much. That was very helpful
with those statistics. And we also let
uh people know that we have availability
there for them to host events like
weddings, anniversaries and such.
>> Yes, Mr. Chair. And and we would
encourage people to contact Botanic
Garden staff um for that scheduling.
There are um events almost daily. And um
uh I'll just highlight too I think um
the education opportunities for school
age children at the Psmith Children's
Village are booked a year in advance.
>> That's great. Really good. Thank you,
Mr. Chairman.
>> Councilman Wolf.
>> Thank you, Mr. Chairman. Through you, um
Mr. Buyers, thank you very much for all
of your work on this your longtime
commitment to it. Um and your work with
the staff. I mean, having Mr. Sanchez,
Director Sanchez, and his um staff
working with you is um a um a real
testament to to
partnership that uh has has just
produced enormously positive results. Um
I live a block from there. I walk by it
every day uh practically and um it's
such a such an incredible amenity and
and just for the general public and
I hope people understand that what what
we do here and what we what the
important work of this committee and all
of the people here is is the absolute
foundation of of an active growing
responsible city. Um this is exactly
what we want to see happen which is
private citizens on the foundation
getting together raising money and
supporting uh projects that that are
essential to the the growth of of one of
the the the most important amenities we
have. And so this is this is not city
government wasting time, wasting energy,
spending money frivolously. It it it
really is and and all the things we do
and have done today and will do are our
core business of the city and uh it's
supported by so many people and it's and
it is so significant uh for us and and I
really just want to compliment you and
thank you Mr. Buyers for being here.
>> Thank you.
>> Any further public comment in the room?
Any
public comment online?
>> Mr. Miller, you can unmute yourself.
>> Testing. Testing. Can you hear me?
>> We can hear you.
>> Um, great. Uh, members of the committee,
Charles Miller, I'm speaking strictly to
item 33B as in boy. Is that correct?
This is the Botanic Gardens EAT garden
construction bid.
>> Correct. Um, I want to acknowledge
upfront that the $854,892
in capital is fully funded by the
Friends of the Botanic Gardens. My
concern today is strictly regarding
municipal liabilities. Moments ago, Mr.
Sanchez confirmed on the live record
that the community recreation and events
department will assist with the
construction management of this project.
Is that is that correct?
>> Correct. Okay. Well, um, in that case,
this raises two immediate financial
questions for the city. Um, question
one, if, uh, donor funds run dry mid
construction during grading or
foundation work, what is the city's
financial overrun exposure?
>> Is there anybody that can answer that?
>> Mr. chair through you Jason Sanchez
community reckoning events uh the
Botanic Garden the friends of the
Botanic Garden Foundation have fully
funded already cash in hand uh the funds
necessary to con to complete this
project. Well, well, it it just um kind
of shows that that the price of of
construction is increasing as time
passes and and so I was just wondering
if if for some reason those funds uh run
dry um mid construction, is there any
kind of uh financial overrun exposure
that the city's going to be um having to
deal with?
>> Mr. chair through you. In this contract,
we also built a force account for
unforeseen problems that we may run
into. Hopefully, we don't and hopefully
throughout this project um the funds
that we have allocated in the contract
will cover the entire contract. If we do
reach that point, we would have to do a
contract mod and we would figure out
what the funding mechanism would be at
that time.
>> I see. I see. Okay. And then, um Thank
you. And then,
>> Mr. Miller, your comments have to go
through the chair every
>> Oh, I'm sorry. uh uh
uh chairman through you. Is that how I I
do that? Uh what what is the five-year
city maintenance cost projection for
this new facility?
>> Mr. Chair, you I don't have that number
off the top of my head, but I would do
my best to provide it to you before
council meeting on Monday.
>> Uh Mr. Chair through you. Thank you. Um,
just to finish up here, uh, donated
capital does not equal free city
services. Um, city staff time and future
maintenance represent real municipal
costs. Um, because of that reason, I
urge a no vote until finance receives a
verified overrun contingency and a
5-year upkeep projection. Thank you.
>> Thank you for your comments,
>> Mr. Chairman. Mr.
I've been thinking about this for a long
time. Um, but I I I uh I think frankly
Mr. Miller is abusing his privileges on
Zoom. Um, I don't even know whether Mr.
Miller is real or a bot. Um, I um I
think if Mr. Miller wants to speak to us
and continue to address us, he ought to
come to our meetings and appear in
person. This is not a radio talk show.
This is not a group therapy session. Um
there's the old saying about familiarity
breeds contempt.
Anonymity breeds contempt on both sides
of this uh discussion. And so I would I
would ask and I'm if and I may ask the
mayor at the full council meeting to um
instruct that Mr. Miller if he wants to
make comments to us that he appear in
person in council chambers and um and uh
so that we can uh actually verify that
um he's not just a chat GPT robot. Thank
you.
>> Mr. Miller, is there any uh thing that
would keep you from appearing in front
of this committee or the governing body
in person?
Um, I'm I'm going to go ahead and
continue to proceed with what I have uh
for the rest of the meeting. Um,
however, I I I really am kind of taken
aback by this uh and and maybe I'll I'll
respond if there's some to type of
official uh you know, message to me, but
I believe that the point of order. I
can't really order that, but I believe
it's a point of order is in uh um order
here for this because um I I think that
it's it's not relevant. I'm not a chat
GT chat GPT bot obviously. Um so uh
that's all I have.
>> Thank you for your comments. Come back
to the committee. Any further comments
or questions?
>> Can I get a motion?
>> Um Mr. Chairman, I move to accept the
bid in amount not to exceed 854,8921.
>> Second.
It's been moved by Councilman Moody,
second by Councilman Wolf. Any further
comments?
>> Uh, yes, Mr. Chairman. Councilman Moody.
>> Thank you, Mr. Chairman. Through you.
Um, just wanted to also add to uh even
our FFA uh programs through our schools
would also benefit from this. That was
forgot to mention. So, but I support it.
Thank you.
>> Hey, all those in favor signify by
saying I.
>> I. Seeing that that vote is unanimous,
the recommendation of the finance
committee will be to approve at the next
meeting of the governing body. Next
item, please.
>> Mr. Chair, I do have to excuse myself to
go to a meeting uh for my full-time job.
>> Okay. Thanks for
>> day job. Excuse me.
Let the record show that Councilman
White left at 1:32 uh p.m. We're on item
number 33 C, consideration of bid number
E-14-26
for furnishing residential automated
refuge carts, 9565 gallons for the
sanitation division.
>> Staff report.
>> Good afternoon, Craig Lavoy
from public works. This contract is for
furnishing us with residential automatic
carts from 95 to 65gallon minimal size
for the sanitation division. This is
with Rick Pacific Company. They are the
lowest responsible bid for $24,884
and I would recommend approval.
>> Any questions or comments from the
committee for staff?
Go to public comment in the room.
Seeing none, public comment online.
Seeing none, we'll bring it back to the
committee. Uh, any comments on this item
from the committee?
>> Can I get a motion?
>> Mr. Chairman, I move to accept a bid
from Rare Pacific Company amount not to
exceed $24,884.
>> Second.
>> It's been moved by Councilman Moody,
second by Councilman Wolf. Any further
discussion? All in favor signify by
saying I.
And that that vote is unanimous. The
recommendation of the finance committee
will be to approve at the next meeting
of the governing body. Next item,
>> number 33D, consideration of bid number
E15-26,
furnishing 1.5 cubic yard rear load
dumpsters for the sanitation division.
>> Staff report.
>> Yes, Greg Lavoy, public works. This is
for our 1 and a half cubic yard rear
load dumpsters for our sanitation
division. This is with Kois Brothers
Equipment for supplying us what we need.
And that's $88,472.
and I would recommend approval.
>> Any questions for staff from the
committee?
Any public comment in the room?
Any public comment online?
Come back to the committee. Can I get a
motion?
>> Mr. Chairman, I move to accept the bid
of Co Brothers Equipment in an amount
not to exceed $88,472.
>> Second. It's been moved by Councilman
Wolf, second by Councilman Moody.
Further comments?
Seeing none, all in favor signify by
saying I.
Seeing that there's none opposed, the
recommendation of the finance committee
will be to approve at the next meeting
of the governing body. Next item
>> number 33E, consideration of bid number
E-7-26
for furnishing vitamus asphalt hot mix,
tac oil, and cold mix on an annual basis
for the city of Cheyenne Street and LA
division. Staff report
>> Vicki Nichek public works. This is for
our annual aotment of hot mix asphalt
hot mix uh cold mix and tack oil. We use
these uh items as m for maintenance in
the rideway to help provide a safe
transportation system for the traveling
public. I recommend approval and I'm
happy to answer any questions.
>> Questions from the committee to staff.
>> Uh Mr. Chairman, thank you through you.
Um thank you Director Nimichek. um is
what impact is um inflation and um all
the other things that we're seeing
having on having on um your ability to
purchase um these absolutely essential
items for our street maintenance
programs. Director,
>> Mr. Chair, through you uh last year
actually the price on our TAC oil which
is per gallon went from $4.80 80 to
$6.25
this year per gallon. Um so that has
some impact. All however our uh
asphalt hot mix is down a dollar
from86.50 to8550
and our cold mix is down $55 a ton from
$250 a um a ton to 195. So it's kind of
been fluctuating. I think we hit it at a
good time. Any
further comments from committee to
staff?
Go to public comment in the room.
Any public comment online?
Seeing none. Can I get a motion?
>> Uh, Mr. Chairman, I move to accept a bid
from Simon Contracts for Patumis Asphalt
Hot Mixing Coal Mixing amount not to
exceed $400 95,750
and bid from JTL Group Incorporated
u doing business as Knife River for Taco
Oil in amount not to exceed $37,500
for a total of $533,250.
>> Second, Mr. Chairman. It's been moved by
Councilman Moody, seconded by Councilman
Wolf.
Any further discussion? Can I get a
motion?
No.
All those in favor signify by saying I
see there's none opposed, the
recommendation of the finance committee
will be to approve at the next meeting
of the governing body. Next item,
>> number 33F, consideration to purchase
between the city of Cheyenne and Musco
Sports Sliding LLC for the purchase of a
mobile video trailer for the community
recreation and events department.
>> Staff report. Mr. Chair, Jason Sanchez,
Community Recreation and Events. Before
you and for your consideration is uh a
purchase of a video wall. This is a a
tool that we've rented over the years
for Fridays on the Plaza. Um, a lot of
what we do for the community, Fridays on
the Plaza Super Day, many of the events
that we do are at no cost or at minimal
cost. We rely on sponsors to be able to
put on uh to fund the majority of the
events that we host. And this piece of
equipment we feel would has the
potential to generate significant
revenue for our department to be able to
continue hosting these events.
Based on the conservative number, we
have at least 55,000 uh attendees for
Fridays on the Plaza annually. And so
over a 15-year period with this
acquisition, over 825,000 people would
see this wall. That would that doesn't
include our numbers for Super Day or any
of the other events we host. And if we
were to generate at least $30,000 a year
for uh advertisement at our events on
this wall, we would generate over
$450,000
over a 15-year period. Again, these are
funds that we would desperately need to
continue hosting the events that we are
able to do for free. Um when I say free,
we are blessed to have a very supportive
community that helps us with
sponsorships. Um some ideas that I have
besides using it for Fridays on the
plaza and for day would be we have
helped um the DDA the last couple years
with providing an inflatable movie
screen for their movies in the park.
This would take place of that inflatable
screen if they choose to do that or
offer that opportunity again.
Um, I think it would be a great tool for
us to do a recording or a welcome uh to
our guests during Frontier Days and put
this out for all the folks standing in
line for the pancake breakfast or for
the parade to have it up on the plaza
just doing a sizzle rule of all the
things there are to do in Cheyenne
things that they could uh participate
in. Um, the the list goes on and on. I
could swing ideas all day on on ways we
would be able to utilize this piece of
equipment. Um, knowing that we had
rented this in the past and what we felt
would be possible if we acquired it, we
applied for a grant through MET and we
were successful in receiving a $50,000
grant to apply toward the purchase of
this piece of equipment. We also have a
grant match of $50,000 and the balance
would come out of my equipment fund. Um,
I stand by for questions and ask for
your support.
>> Councilman Moody.
>> Yep. Thank you, Mr. Chairman. Thank you,
Mr. Sanchez. Very helpful. Um, probably
another usage I'll just ask do could
this also be used even for emergencies
if needed as well too because that was
just popping through my head if there's
burned bands or you know red flag
warnings.
>> Mr. Chair you absolutely I you know
again uh the neighborhood night outs um
any events in any of the different wards
it's a mobile uh display so we'd be able
to utilize it anywhere. Uh the the uh
spec on this is that we have a diesel
power generator on it. So it would last
30 hours. So we're not even at the mercy
of having to plug in somewhere. We could
do that, but this has its own power
source as well. So multiple uses.
>> Council Wolf.
>> Uh Mr. Chairman, thank you through you.
Um Mr. Sanchez, thank you. I mean, this
this looks like a tremendous piece of
equipment to have. Do can you do you
have the storage space for it and and so
it's secure?
>> Mr. Chair, through you. Yes, we do. We
have uh two different areas that we
would store it indoors during the winter
months and during the summer. Um it also
has a warranty. So 11 year on a
warranty, 5 year on the labor. So um we
would take good care of it. I I relate
it similar to our stage, right? When we
purchased the stage seven years ago,
look at how it's enhanced the events
that we have in the community and we
store that at our park maintenance shop.
>> Any further questions for staff?
Go to public comment in the room.
>> Corey Li through you chair to committee.
I'm just here to uh support Director
Sanchez and his staff and his big brain.
Um because he kind of highlighted to us
downtown property owners the many uses
not just downtown but through the whole
community and a lot of what they do is
intangible. It just creates a vibe um
that our city is a great destination and
I think that this would really go a long
way towards that effort. Thank you.
Hello, Sophia Mays, executive director
of the DDA. Again, I would echo what
Miss Loft 3 just said and then also what
director Sanchez has spoken to you about
today. The one thing or many things but
a huge um feedback we get a lot is that
a lot of folks don't know what's
happening in this community and that
while that will take a multi-pronged
approach this is a very easy way to
distribute that information especially
at major events that CRA hosts um
there's uh director Sanchez also
mentioned the DDA's uh previous screen
in the green u movie in the parks uh
we're in discussions with some folks
especially at the Wyoming Independent
Film Festival
And um we're looking to potentially
co-host and potentially use that screen
for this among other events that this
could um could enhance. Um we fully
support this consideration. Thank you.
>> Director, do you know when you would be
able to take delivery of this after we
finalize it?
>> Mr. Chair, um if we receive support
through the governing body, the company
said they could deliver within 30 days.
So, we're hoping to have it here by the
first Friday on the plaza.
>> Good.
Any further public comment in the room?
Any public comment online?
>> Mr. Miller, you can go ahead.
>> Um, this is Charles Miller. Can you hear
me?
>> Yes, we can.
>> Uh, members of the committee, Charles
Miller. I am speaking strictly to item
33F as in Frank uh the single source
purchase of a mo mobile mobile video
trailer um and to Councilman Wolf as a
very real taxpayer of this county. I am
asking this committee to reject this
exorbitant expenditure. According to
your own sole source memo, this city is
bypassing competitive bidding so the
community recreation and events
department can spend $161,826
on a Musco Max 1710 mobile LED video
screen. Your documents show you are
draining over $61,000 from the fifth
penny sales tax equipment fund. Is that
correct? and also five $50,000 from spot
funds for this single item. Is are those
figures and uh locations correct?
>> Correct.
>> Okay. Um well, two minutes ago uh this
committee authorized half a million
dollars for baseline street maintenance
using an optional sales tax. Approving
six figure luxury electronics while
relying on optional taxes for basic
asphalt and core infrastructure is
financially irresponsible.
This is a purely discretionary purchase
based on speculative sponsorship
revenue. The real human taxpayers of
Cheyenne are watching exactly how you
prioritize our funds today. I urge a no
vote. Thank you.
>> Thank you for your comments. Any further
comments online?
Bring it back to the committee
and I get a motion.
>> Okay. Um Mr. uh Mr. Chairman, I move to
accept the bid in amount not to exceed
$161,826.
>> Second.
>> It's been moved by Councilman Moody,
second by Councilman Wolf. Any further
discussion? Councilman Moody.
>> Thank you, Mr. Chairman. Through you.
Um, thank you everybody for those public
comments. Very helpful and definitely
agree how it would be helpful. Um,
again, as I mentioned, I even think for
emergencies, this would be very helpful,
too. If we run out of signage and
there's, you know, like we had the dust
storm just about a month ago, this would
have been very helpful to know, you
know, which rows are shut down or if
there's trees down, use caution. I think
even from an emergency perspective, this
be helpful. Thank you.
>> And also just to point out, it has a
$50,000 grant from META attached to this
as well.
All those in favor, please signify by
saying I.
Seeing that that is unanimous, the
recommendation of the finance committee
will be to approve at the next meeting
of the governing body. Next item.
>> Other items for the agenda. Modification
to bid number E-4-25
for three fire apparatus for the city of
Cheyenne. Cheyenne Fire Rescue
Department.
Staff report.
Thank you, chairman, members of council,
and uh finance committee. I'm Andrew
Dyorn, fire chief for Cheyenne Fire
Rescue. I want to thank you for the
opportunity to speak before you today um
about something that presented itself
early last week. Uh through our fleet
committee chair, uh Battalion Chief Neil
Durani, we discovered that our
manufacturer has produced a line of fire
trucks that now closely matches the
engines we actually utilize here in
Cheyenne. I'm here this afternoon to
present a strategic opportunity that
allows us to accelerate our commitment
to public safety while demonstrating
high level fiscal stewardship of our
capital funds. As you know, in November
of 2024, we placed an order for three
new fire engines to address our aging
fleet. At that time, due to global
supply chain issues, we were given a
delivery date of January 2029, nearly 2
and a half years away still. Recently,
last Monday to be exact, a unique
opportunity emerged where a high
specification engine nearly identical to
our order became available for delivery
this coming October for $1,428,842,
which is approximately $44,35.
Yeah, $44,356
less than projected to pay in 2029 if
allowed to by voters. By pivoting our
current plan, cancel cancelling one of
our 2029 engine slots, and securing this
unit in October, we can put a new
frontline engine in service 28 months
ahead of schedule. This new engine
features an upgraded pump in a larger
water tank. We will place this newer,
higher capacity unit at station 5. Since
the 2024 engine has already accumulated
higher mileage than the others due to
call volume, the big box stores and
multif family apartment complexes being
built in station 5's area also make this
apparatus placement ideal for water flow
if approved. In turn, we will move a
shorter shorter in length 2024 apparatus
to station 6. This allows us to move the
current 2015 engine in service at
station 6 into our reserve fleet. At
CFR, we've adopted a 12-ear timeline for
frontline apparatus followed by another
eight years in reserve status, which
helps CFR. This will help CFR stay
aligned with that. If this new apparatus
is approved, it will allow us to trade
in reserve engine 15, which was put in
service in the Cheyenne community in
1999.
We are concerned about the safe use of
this reserve apparatus and any costs
associated with keeping it in service
for the next two and a half years.
I am mindful of the date. We have a one%
specific purpose sales and use tax
initiative on the ballot this August
that includes these three trucks. I want
to be clear that this is not a request
for additional funding. This is a
realignment of our existing long-term
plan to protect the taxpayer. By taking
delivery in 2026, we lock in our current
value and insulate the city from three
additional years of inflation and the
rising maintenance costs of our older
fleet. Most importantly, it shows the
voters that we are agile, that if they
choose to support this ballot
initiative, we are ready to put those
dollars to work immediately, not years
down the road. This truck will arrive
ready to serve. I am asking for your
support to execute this contract
modification, ensuring the Cheyenne Fire
Rescue remains ahead of the curve in
both operational readiness and fiscal
responsibility. I am happy to answer any
questions.
>> Questions for the committee for the
chief da
Councilman Wolf.
>> Mr. Chairman, thank you. Through you,
where Chief, where is the station five
located,
>> Chief? Uh through you to uh Councilman
Wolf, that is 4200 Converse Avenue, sir.
>> Councilman Moody.
>> Yep. Thank uh thank you, Chief. Um could
you just like just elaborate to the
public how the older engines how much
fleet maintenance uh there actually is
for that? I know I've talked with the
fleet maintenance people and they've
given me definitely a lot of detail on
that.
>> Yes sir. Our fleet maintenance uh do do
a great job for us. Um they helped us
with this uh actual contract
modification by looking through all of
this but further they do the maintenance
and repairs. Um several different
schedules for uh preventative
maintenance and then all the other
repairs that typically go down. They
handle mostly in shop. Some does have to
be outsourced, but mostly it is in in
shop and they they they do the best job
they can for us and um keep our keep our
citizens safe by keeping our fire trucks
on the road.
>> Thank you.
>> Thank you. Thanks, Chief. We'll go to
public comment in the room.
>> Any public comment online?
Seeing none, back to the committee. Any
other comments or ready for motion?
>> Uh, Mr. Chairman, I move to approve the
savings of $44,356.
It's
>> been moved by Councilman Moody, second
by Councilman Wolf. All in favor signify
by saying I.
>> Seeing that that vote is unanimous, the
recommendation of the finance committee
will be to approve at the next meeting
of the governing body. Seeing that there
is no more business in front of this
committee, we are adjourned.